<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 05:43:37 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science and Programming 🖱️</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/programming_and_science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 05:43:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/programming_and_science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Programming is often mentioned in an applied context. 🖥️ It seems that only mobile applications, Internet systems and special effects for cinema are created with its help. But initially programming was intended to solve scientific problems. In addition, programming itself is a science, which will be useful to learn about for those who decide to link their careers with computer development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is a highly oriented style of programming for scientific computing. It is distinguished from other types of programming by the extreme correctness and stability of the final product, the strict separation of scientific and interface parts, the individuality of algorithms, and the predominance of efficiency over universality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is at the heart of any modern global research. All advanced technologies - from quantum computers to space programs - would not be possible without scientific programmers who can provide scientists with a reliable and accurate tool for making discoveries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of branches of science directly depend on the level of development of scientific programming. So, unmanned vehicles, “smart” management systems for urban and agricultural management, stock exchanges are waiting for their implementation; waiting for robotics, genetic engineering, artificial intelligence that surpasses human capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;specializations-&#34;&gt;Specializations 🙎‍♂️&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists use various programming languages, the choice of which depends on the type of problem and the preferences of the author. Historically, the first high-level programming language is Fortran, it has many debugged libraries of mathematical statistics and libraries for solving differential equations, which is relevant for economics and biology, respectively. Python has a simpler syntax, which is also suitable for programming mathematical calculations. The Python language is used for data processing in mathematics, physics, economics, biology, chemistry and can work with some other &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; languages: Fortran, C++, C#.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In turn, C# allows you to program on the .NET platform, adapt the program to the common language runtime (CLR), and accelerate development within the framework of operational scientific sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-future-of-the-programmer-scientist-profession-&#34;&gt;The future of the programmer-scientist profession 🧑‍💼&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Programming drives science 💻, which drives technological progress. Inventions that were considered revolutionary yesterday serve everyday needs in the 21st century: a microwave oven, a mobile phone, an 8-bit home computer. It depends on the programmer-scientist what peaks science will reach today and which of them will enter every house tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hands of the programmer-scientist ⌨️ are the tools not only to develop the industry, but also to improve the overall quality of life. Such a specialist increases the prognostic function of humanity, helping to predict and prevent climate, financial, and humanitarian disasters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What was my last week like?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last_week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 05:43:10 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last_week3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every week I make a wish that I will spend the next week more productively and interestingly. Surely, you have already noticed this in my regular posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for this week, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to say whether it worked out this time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand 🐇, I did not make much progress in my studies this week, although I still answered in class and did all my homework.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand 🐤, I was able to achieve the goal that I set myself a week ago. I met and talked with friends. We discussed various topics, inflated balloons and walked around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spring is in full swing 🍃 and summer is just around the corner ⛱️! I think many of you are tired, as am I. I assure you that very soon we will be able to relax and take care of ourselves and loved ones. But it takes a little more effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With best wishes, Arina.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 06:28:36 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lets-tell-about-report-&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s tell about report! 📝&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every week&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; we do laboratory work. Then we should prepare a report on our labs. We perform reports for laboratory work in the lightweight markup language &lt;strong&gt;markdown&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-markdown-ℹ&#34;&gt;What is MARKDOWN? ℹ️&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using a plain-text editor. John Gruber and Aaron Swartz created Markdown in 2004 as a markup language that is appealing to human readers in its source code form. Markdown is widely used in blogging, instant messaging, online forums, collaborative software, documentation pages, and readme files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-we-execute-the-report-&#34;&gt;How do we execute the report? 💻&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For each laboratory work, we have a &lt;em&gt;template&lt;/em&gt; that we need to fill in with all the necessary information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title page of the report contains information about the &lt;em&gt;number&lt;/em&gt; of the lab, the &lt;em&gt;topic&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;author&lt;/em&gt; of the report.
Next, we describe the &lt;em&gt;purpose&lt;/em&gt; of the laboratory work, the &lt;em&gt;task&lt;/em&gt;, as well as a &lt;em&gt;theoretical introduction&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then the description of the main part of the work begins. &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description of the work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We should describe the accomplishment of the work as &lt;em&gt;fully and clearly&lt;/em&gt; as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To do this, we can divide the job description into several parts, insert screenshots, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;for-what---&#34;&gt;For what? 🤔 ❓ 💡&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creating a report is an &lt;strong&gt;important stage&lt;/strong&gt; of laboratory work, because it is during the execution of the report that the material is consolidated and its full awareness occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New post about last week again!</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last_week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 06:14:34 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last_week2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago, I decided to spend the next week better than the previous one. And a week ago I promised that this week would be more colorful and productive&amp;hellip;🥀💮🌼&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-did-i-manage-to-keep-my-promise&#34;&gt;But did I manage to keep my promise?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;didn&amp;rsquo;t waste any time&lt;/strong&gt; this week again. I studied a lot 📚, did all the tasks 🖋️, read 📖, watched TV shows 📺. But unfortunately, I didn&amp;rsquo;t even get to meet my friends this week 😭.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-this-case-is-it-possible-to-call-this-week-productive-&#34;&gt;In this case, is it possible to call this week productive? 🤔&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that it is &lt;strong&gt;very important&lt;/strong&gt; to find time for rest and communication. And I didn&amp;rsquo;t succeed. I hope I won&amp;rsquo;t make this mistake again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;will-the-next-week-more-productive&#34;&gt;Will the next week more productive?!&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure I can be more productive next week, so I won&amp;rsquo;t promise it this time. However, I can promise myself to &lt;strong&gt;try to do everything I need&lt;/strong&gt; next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your attention! See you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;💖&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 05:56:09 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Markdown is a lightweight markup language for creating formatted text using a plain-text editor. John Gruber and Aaron Swartz created Markdown in 2004 as a markup language that is appealing to human readers in its source code form. Markdown is widely used in blogging, instant messaging, online forums, collaborative software, documentation pages, and readme files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;basic-information-about-markdown&#34;&gt;Basic information about Markdown:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To create a title, use the sign ( # ), for example, look above! Do you see big text? It is the title!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make the text &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;, enclose it in double asterisks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set an &lt;em&gt;italic&lt;/em&gt; font for the text, enclose it in single asterisks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To set &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bold and italicized&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; text, enclose it in triple
asterisks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulleted list can be formatted using asterisks or dashes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is a fact.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ordered list can be formatted using the appropriate numbers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don’t you believe me?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;See for yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementations of Markdown are available for over a dozen programming languages; in addition, many platforms and frameworks support Markdown. For example, Markdown plugins exist for every major blogging platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I spent last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last_week1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 05:17:42 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last_week1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;has-this-week-been-productive&#34;&gt;Has this week been productive?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week ago, I promised myself that I would spend this week &lt;strong&gt;even more productively&lt;/strong&gt; than last week. I hope I managed to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I was still very busy studying. I did a lot of homework 📖, worked in classes at the university 📚, studied additional material 💻.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course I &lt;strong&gt;did not forget about the rest&lt;/strong&gt;. I managed to watch a couple of episodes of my favorite TV show 🎬, read a little 📚 and meet with friends 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this &lt;strong&gt;was not enough for me to feel good&lt;/strong&gt;, this week I felt very &lt;strong&gt;stressed&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;tired&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, I hope that next week I will be able to distribute time both to study and to rest in order to feel better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;in-general&#34;&gt;In general,&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;spring has finally come! 🌿🌺🌞 We should leave the house more often and go out with our loved ones. But we can do this only after all the cases are finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why I &lt;strong&gt;hope&lt;/strong&gt; that next week will be no less &lt;strong&gt;productive&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;interesting&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Git</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 15:37:13 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lets-talk-about-version-control-git&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about version control Git.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Version Control Systems (VCS)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; are used when several people work on one project. Usually, the main project tree is stored in a local or remote repository, to which access is configured for project participants. When making changes to the project content, the version control system allows you to fix them, combine changes made by different project participants, roll back to any earlier version of the project, if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In classical version control systems, a centralized model is used, assuming a single repository for storing files. Most version control functions are performed by a special server. The project participant (user) receives the version of files he needs before starting work through certain commands. After making changes, the user places the new version in the repository. At the same time, previous versions are not deleted from the central repository and you can return to them at any time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Version control systems support the ability to track and resolve conflicts that may arise when several people work on a single file. You can merge (merge) changes made by different participants (automatically or manually), manually select the desired version, cancel the changes altogether or lock files for modification. Depending on the settings, the lock does not allow other users to get a working copy or prevents changing the working copy of the file by means of the OS file system, thus providing privileged access to only one user working with the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Git version control system is a set of command-line programs. They can be accessed from the terminal by entering the git command with various options. Due to the fact that Git is a distributed version control system, a backup copy of the local storage can be made by simple copying or archiving.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 13:54:59 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-week-has-been-productive&#34;&gt;This week has been productive.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading this post. I will tell. how I spent this week. This week has been quite productive. I completed all my homework, actively worked in classes at the institute. In addition, I also had time to watch TV shows, read a book and meet friends. I plan to do even more next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-review-of-the-week&#34;&gt;My review of the week.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I would like to say that I have worked hard this week. But next week I plan to do it even harder.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
